（フンガ）エジソン…　キュービック・Ｇ。
（メイズ）ダビンチ…　アナ・グラム。
Edison: Cubic Galois.
Da Vinci: Ana Gram.
Galileo: Sakanoue Gammon.
（ダイスマン）ガリレオ…　逆之上ギャモン。
（フンガ）彼らを　大門カイトから
引き離すことはできませんでした。
We failed to separate them from Daimon Kaito.
（メイズ）申し訳ございません。
We are terribly sorry.
（ルーク）フッ。
作戦は順調に進んでいる。
The plan is progressing well.
次のターゲットは…。
The next target is...
（フンガ）大門カイト？
（ダイスマン）いや　でも…。
Daimon Kaito?
But...
仲間を引き離し　大門カイトを
１人にするという作戦では…。
Wasn't the plan to get rid of his friends and make him proceed alone?
彼の心から　永遠を奪う。
I will take eternity from his heart.
永遠？
ビショップ。
Eternity...?
Bishop.
大門カイトも　すでに
日本に戻っております。
Daimon Kaito has already returned to Japan.
そして　計画どおりに彼を…。
It's all going according to the plan.
それでいい。　フフフッ。
Very well.
（カイト）おっさん！
どういうこった？！
Hey, Principal! What's going on?!
今日という今日は
話を聞かせてもらおう…。
You said you would... tell me... today...
クソっ！　どこ行きやがった？！
Dammit, where the hell has he gone?
（ソウジ）分からないんだ…。
軸川先輩？
I don't know either.
Jikugawa? You don't know?
分からねえって…。
僕も困ってるんだけどね。
It's plenty of trouble for me too.
kimi no nounai he shinnyuu nemutteiru sukima ni
I infiltrate your brain while you're sleeping.
Baby, open the gate!
fukuzatsu sugi sekyuriti kakusareru to abakitaku naru
The security's too tough, but I want to expose what's hidden.
barabara ni chirabatteiru pasuwado wo hiroi atsume
I gather the pieces of the shattered password.
kakushin ni sematte iku sono shoutai wo misete
I get close to the core. Show me who you really are!
kantan ni kuria dekinai saki nante motto yomenai
I can't clear it easily. I can't even see what lies ahead.
kaidoku fukanou sumairu kikenna pazuru
Your indecipherable smile is a hazardous puzzle.
rokku sareta doa aru nara zutto tataite miru beki kazana hiraku wa
When you see a locked door, you should just hit it until a crack opens.
eien ni hodokenai nazo nanka wa nai
There's no mystery that lasts forever!
makiokosu, it's a supernova
I made it, it's a supernova!
tobikiri shigekitekina hirameki wo agemashou
Let's flash so bright it'd hurt!
Misskey-Misskey La-Tu-Ma
yume no naka it's a supernova
In my dreams, it's a supernova!
watashi wa sou brain diver
Yeah, I'm the brain diver!
kimi ga sagashi motometeru kotae ni nareru made
Until I can find the answer you're looking for...
Brain diver!
Truth
（ノノハ）学園長が行方不明？！
僕たちが日本を離れている間にね。
The principal has disappeared?
Yes, while we were overseas.
こんなときに　どうしたんだろう？
（キュービック）もしかしたら　ＰＯＧに…。
What could it be at a time like this?
Could it be the POG...?
He might've gotten attacked like me.
（ギャモン）襲われたってのか？！
俺みてえに…。
だとしても　そう簡単に
やられるはずがない。
Even so, he wouldn't go down that easily.
（アナ）バロバロとソウジは　ファイ・ブレインや
神のパズルのことを知っていた。
Baro-Baro and Soji both knew about the Phi Brain and the Divine Puzzle.
今は　学園長を信じて
待つしかない。
We have no choice but to believe in him and wait.
…って　言われてもよ。
本当に心当たりないの？
Even if he says that...
You really have no idea?
あるわけねえだろ？
How could I?
But he was the one who adopted and raised you, wasn't he?
でも　カイトを引き取って
育ててくれた人なんでしょ？
…つったってよ　イギリスに
留学させられたっきりで→
Yeah, that's just it...
Right after I got sent to England with a scholarship, he called me back, and here we are.
呼び戻されたと思ったら
これだぜ。
大体　おやじと　おふくろの
知り合いだったってこと以外→
Also, I don't really know anything about him, except that he knew my parents.
なんも知らねえし…。
ふ～ん…　そっか。
I see.
カイトのお父さん　お母さんと
友達なら　信用できるかもね。
If he was friends with your parents, then I guess we can trust him.
何だよ　それ？
ヘヘッ　パズル　よく作って
遊んでくれたよね。
What do you mean?
He made puzzles and played with us.
ヘッ　１つも解けなかったくせに。
うっ…。
Heh, you couldn't solve a single one.
おじさんたちのパズルが
難しすぎたんだよ！
Those puzzles were too hard!
相手が子供だからって
手加減するのは失礼だってな。
It's rude to hold back just because your opponent's a kid.
いつでも　パズルにゃ　本気だった。
懐かしいなぁ！
They were always serious about puzzles.
That brings back memories!
カイトんちのパズル部屋　でっかくって
パズルが　いっぱい置いてあって…。
The puzzle room at your place. It was full of puzzles!
わ～ん　ん～。
回想
これが　こっち。
よっし！　できた！
This... this way...?
I'm done!
うっ　う～ん。　私だって
回想
負けないんだから！　う～ん。
I won't lose!
回想
ヒント　教えてやろうか？
いいもん。
I'll give you a hint.
I don't need it!
The memories of their puzzles still live on in me.
おやじたちがくれた
パズルへの思いは　俺ん中で生きてる。
[TEL]
あっ？！　クソっ！　またか！
Damn, this again?
あっ！
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
今の…　何？
What was that?
おやじと　おふくろの
死んだ場所だ。
It's the place where my parents died.
えっ？！
どういうつもりだ…。
What are they planning?
行けってのか？　俺に…
あの場所へ。　ルーク！
Are you telling me to go there? Rook!
つ～かよお！
なんで　お前らまで居るんだ！
Can you please tell me...
Why the hell are all of you here?!
はい　は～い！
駅弁タイムの始まりだ！
All right! Time for the packed lunches I got at the station!
じゃあ　釜飯がいい人？
Who wants the pot rice?
は～い！
僕は　リンゴ弁当。
Me!
I'll have the apple one.
はい　はい。　キューちゃんは？
じゃあ　幕の内で。
And you, Cubie?
I'll take the variety one.
ごめんね　みんな。　軸川先輩。
Sorry, guys. And Jikugawa.
I couldn't ignore it after I heard the story.
話を聞いた以上
放ってはおけないよ。
ん～。　釜飯　うま～！
This pot rice is so good!
Gammon, yours is a beef dish!
ギャモン君には　これ！　牛肉弁当！
ギュ　ギュ～って！
So that you won't beef!
カイトには…　な　な　なんと
パズル弁当！
And Kaito's is, guess what, a Puzzle Lunch!
Okudera   the Genius's
Puzzle Lunch
ゾロゾロと　遠足じゃ　あるまいし
罠かもしれねえんだぞ。
It's not even that far. And it's probably a trap.
僕は　カイトの友達だよ！
はぁ？！
I'm your friend!
友達が一緒にいるのは
当然じゃないか！
It's natural for friends to stay together!
カイトが　なんて言おうと
僕は　絶対に一緒に行くからね！
Whatever you say, I'll tag along!
キュービック…。
Cubic...
学園長が居ない間　僕には　君たち
生徒を見守る義務があるからね。
It's my duty to watch over the students while the principal is gone.
ご苦労なこって。
No need.
I think... it's fun to go far away together!
アナが思うに
みんなで旅行って　楽しい。
みんなで食べる
お弁当もおいしい…。
The food's better when we eat it together too!
１人で遠くへ行っても
つまんないよ～。　カイト！
It's boring to go far away alone, Kaito.
別に遊びに行くわけじゃねえよ。
そっか。
I'm not doing this for fun.
Right!
カイトが…　遠くに…。
心の声
Kaito's going far away...
ここが…。
Is this it?
This is...
これは…。
あの時のパズル…。
That puzzle from back then!
But this is way more complicated.
だが　こいつの方が数段　複雑だ。
あの時のやつは　こいつのレプリカか？
That was the replica of this?
This feeling...
この感じ…　こいつは…。
This is a Fools' Puzzle!
愚者のパズルだ！
じゃあ　おじさんと　おばさんは
愚者のパズルで死んだってこと？！
That means your parents died in a Fools' Puzzle?
（バロン）来ましたか。
あっ。
So you came.
Principal!
学園長？！
無事だったのですか？
You're okay? But why are you here?
しかし　なぜ　こんなところに？
Kaito's parents?
カイトの　お父さんとお母さん？
えっ？！
なんだよ　こりゃ？！
What is this?
Daimon Kaito observation records.
（カイトの父・アキラ）
「大門カイト　観察記録」。
観察記録だと？
はっ。
Observation records?
（アキラ）「５月３日　パズルナンバーＡ８７を
５分１４秒で解答。→
May 3rd. Puzzle no. A-87.
Kaito solved it in 5 minutes and 14 seconds.
成人ソルヴァーの平均　８分３０秒を
大きく上回る」。
This far exceeds the average adult Solver's time of 8 minutes and 30 seconds.
ソルヴァー？
Solver?
June 4th. He has trouble with B-23.
（カイトの母・シズカ）「６月４日　Ｂ－２３に
苦戦。　数式系のパズルが弱点か？」。
Could numeric puzzles be his weakness?
（アキラ）「６月１５日　Ｂ－２３をクリア。→
June 15th. He solved B-23.
こちらの指導を待たず
自分で解を発見」。
He found the solution without asking for our help.
カイト　もう　やめよう…。
Kaito, stop it...
（シズカ）「予定を早め　明日より
特別プログラムでの指導を始める」。
We will start the special program tomorrow, ahead of schedule.
「以上　報告終了」。
This concludes our report.
「大門カイトの育成と観察を
続けます」。
We will continue observing and raising Daimon Kaito.
「ＰＯＧジャパン　大門アキラ」。
「同じく　シズカ」。
POG Japan, Daimon Akira.
Likewise, Shizuka.
うっ　うふふっ…
ウ　ウソだよ　こんなの。
This is just a prank, isn't it?
あっ　ＴＶで見たよ。
最近のＣＧは　すっごいんだって。
I've seen this CG stuff on TV that looks totally real.
何でも作れちゃうの！
ＰＯＧ…。
They can fake anything!
POG...
若い俳優さんがね
おじいちゃんになったりして…。
They just found some young actors to play your parents...
父さんと　母さんが…　ＰＯＧ。
My parents were in the POG...
そ　それから…　それから…。
And... And...
あぁ？
ダメ。　違うよ　カイト！
Don't. That's not it, Kaito!
（バロン）本当です。　あの２人は
ＰＯＧのメンバーでした。
It's true.
They were members of the POG.
あっ。
学園長！　なんで　そんなこと？！
Why are you doing this, Principal?
カイト君…　君は　ファイ・ブレインとして
目覚めるための特殊な教育を受け→
Kaito. You were raised and specially educated to aid your Phi Brain awakening.
育てられたのです。
がっ　学園長？！
P-Principal!
あの２人は　そのために選ばれた
ＰＯＧでも指折りのギヴァー。
They were especially talented Givers of the POG selected for this purpose.
ウソだ。
君の…　実の両親ではありません。
You lie.
They weren't your real parents.
（バロン）彼らに預けられる以前の
君の記録は　どこにもありません。
There are no records of you before you were placed in their care.
カイト…。
なんで　んなこと知ってんだよ？
Kaito...
Why do you know all this?!
（バロン）それは　私も…
ＰＯＧの一員だからです。
That is because I am...
a member of the POG as well.
ウソだ。　ウソだ～～～～！
It can't be.
That can't be!
（ビショップ）
解道バロン　ミッションを完了しました。
Kaido Baron has completed his mission.
ミッション？
Mission?
思い出の中の　父親と母親…。
だが　それは偽りだ。
His parents as he remembers them... were fakes.
彼らは　任務を
遂行していたにすぎない。
They merely did their duty.
大門カイトの両親を演じるというね。
Their duty to be Daimon Kaito's parents.
その事実を　両親の死んだ場所で
解道バロンに告げさせる。
Kaido Baron tells him the truth at the place where they died.
で　では　大門カイトの永遠とは？
Th-Then the eternity in his heart...
彼の心で　生き続ける両親。
...was the memory of his parents.
仲間を引き離したとしても
２人の思い出があるかぎり→
Even if we managed to separate him from his friends,
as long as he has those memories, he would never be alone.
大門カイトは　決して
１人にはならない。
その永遠を…　僕が奪う…。
And I took that eternity away.
そして　新たな永遠を…。
And I'll give him a new one.
カイト君。
来んな！
Kaito...
Stay away!
聞いてほしいことがあります。
I want to tell you something.
てめえも　俺を
だましてたんじゃねえか！
You lied to me all this time!
父さんも　母さんも…　俺を！
So did Mom and Dad...
お願いです。　聞いてください。
Please. Listen.
俺を道具に…　寄って　たかって
俺を道具にしてたのかよ！
You used me... You all just used me!
もう嫌だ！　何が　パズルだ！
I've had enough! To hell with puzzles!
あっ。
黙って話を聞け！
Shut up and listen!
もう　時間がない。
私は負けたんだ…。
We have no time. I lost.
もう私に　ＰＯＧを
止めることはできません。
I can't stop the POG anymore.
ですから　最後の抵抗を試みます。
So, I will try to defy them one last time.
私は　今からＰＯＧを裏切る。
すぐに追われる身となるでしょう。
I will betray the POG now, and they will chase me to the end of the world.
But first, I will tell you everything.
その前に　すべてを
伝えておきます。
ルーク様。
放っておけ。
Sir Rook.
Let him be.
どんな言葉も　もう　カイトには
届かない…。　フフッ。
No words can reach Kaito anymore.
（バロン）私は　√学園の
学園長であると同時に→
I have been the principal of the Root Academy,
「セクションΦ」と呼ばれる
極秘部署の責任者でした。
and at the same time the head of the special division called Section Phi.
セクションΦ？
Section Phi?
そうです。　ファイ・ブレインの子供たちを
指導し育てる部署で→
Yes. It is a special division with the sole purpose of raising children of the Phi Brain.
軸川君も　そのメンバーです。
えっ？！　軸川先輩も　ＰＯＧ？！
Jikugawa is a member as well.
What? He's in the POG?!
学園長…　一体？！
Principal, what are you...
ファイ・ブレインを育成し　完成させ　神の
パズルを解き　神の書を手に入れる。
Raise the Phi Brain, reach it, solve the Divine Puzzle, and get the Divine Revelations.
それが　ピタゴラス伯爵の
野望なのです。
That is the goal of Count Pythagoras.
学園長　それ以上は…。
Principal, you shouldn't...
あんたも　そいつに
加担してんだな。
You helped him, didn't you?
（バロン）そもそもＰＯＧは　依頼者の
思いにふさわしいパズルを作り→
POG was an organization that constructed puzzles to fit the client's needs,
財を封じ　管理する組織でした。
sealed a treasure inside, and watched over it.
√学園も　そんなギヴァーを育成する
ために　ＰＯＧが設立したのです。
The Root Academy was founded to raise Givers capable of that.
ですが　ピタゴラス伯爵が実権を握り
すべてが変わってしまいました。
However, Count Pythagoras seized power and everything changed.
てめえは　違うってのかよ？
And you were different or something?!
（バロン）私は　伯爵の命令を
実行すると見せかけて→
I wanted to keep acting as if I was under the Count's orders,
先に神の書を手に入れ　この世から
消し去ろうと考えていたのです。
get the Divine Revelations first, and then erase it from existence.
消し去る？
神の書を巡る争いは→
Erase it?
History is full of battles centered around it.
歴史上　幾度も
繰り広げられてきました。
There will be no end to that as long as it exists. Therefore...
神の書が存在するかぎり　絶える
ことはないでしょう。　ならば…。
でも　あなたは　そのために
カイトを　愚者のパズルに挑戦させた。
But you made Kaito challenge Fools' Puzzles for that.
キューちゃん
学園長は　そこまでは…。
Cubie, the principal surely didn't...
少なくとも止めませんでしたよね。
You didn't stop him, that's for sure!
なんと責められようと
しかたありません。
You have every right to accuse me.
愚者のパズルは　急激な成長を
促しますが　命の危険を伴います。
Fools' Puzzles contribute to extreme progress, but endanger the challenger's life.
しかも　人間の心を持たない
道具しか育てない。
They create nothing but heartless tools.
私は　愚者のパズルを使わずに　ファイ・
ブレインを育てるつもりでしたが→
I wanted to raise the Phi Brain without using Fools' Puzzles.
ＰＯＧの動きが
それを許しませんでした。
The POG wouldn't allow me to do that.
ですが　カイト君の両親は違います。
However, Kaito's parents were different.
君の両親は　伯爵の命令に反して
君を　実の子供のように→
They went against the Count's orders and came to love you as their own child.
心から愛してしまった。
ファイ・ブレインの成長を急いだ
ＰＯＧは→
The POG wanted to hurry your progress
まだ幼い君を　この愚者のパズルに
挑ませようとしました。
and make you challenge this Fools' Puzzle at such a young age.
しかし　彼らは　その命令に背き→
They disobeyed their orders and tried to solve the puzzle instead of you.
君に代わって　自分たちで
パズルを解こうとしたのです。
To save Kaito?
カイトを助けるために？
ええ。　ですが…。
Indeed. However...
（バロン）
途中で　これが　パズルであり→
You realized that this was a puzzle and saw your parents fall to their deaths.
両親のカゴが落ちることにも
気づいた君は→
伯爵の期待を受け　私のところに
預けられたのです。
The Count saw your potential and put me in charge of you.
ウソだ！　そんな話
信じろってのかよ？！
It's all lies! How could I believe anything you say?!
だって　あの２人は…！
Then why did they...
You know that better than anyone else.
その答えは　君が
一番よく知っているはずです。
あの映像は？
That video...
（アキラ）「ほ～ら　カイト」。
（シズカ）「ジャジャーン！」。
Look, Kaito!
Tada!
「うわ～っ！」
（シズカ）「せ～の！」。
One, two...
Happy birthday, Kaito!
（アキラ・シズカ）
「カイト　お誕生日おめでとう！」。
（アキラ）「あ～！　ハハッ」。
（シズカ）「さあ　ケーキ切りましょうね」。
Now, let's cut the cake.
「イチゴ！
イチゴ載ってるとこが　いい！」。
Strawberries! I want the one with strawberries!
（シズカ）「了解！　イチゴいっぱい。
じゃあ　ここだ！」。
Roger that! There lots of strawberries for you! Here you go!
「ねぇねぇ　今日は
パズルの部屋　行かないの？」。
Hey, we're not going to the puzzle room today?
（シズカ）「ええ　今日は
こっちで遊びましょう」。
No, let's have fun here today!
That doesn't matter. Look, here's your present!
（アキラ）「そんなことより
ほら　プレゼントだぞ～！」。
What the hell is that?
なんだ　こりゃ？
こんなものを見せて　一体？！
Why is he showing him that?
Whoa! Can I open it?
「うわ～っ！　ねえ　開けていい？」。
（アキラ）「おお　開けろ　開けろ！」。
Sure, go on, go on!
（シズカ）「何かなぁ？」。
What could it be?
「ハ　ハッ！　ありがとう！
お父さん！　お母さん！」。
Thank you so much, Mommy, Daddy!
解道バロンの端末を
強制的に停止させました。
I shut off Kaido Baron's terminal.
何だ　今の声は？
あれは　演技なのか？
What was that voice? Is that acting?
あれは…　あれは　一体？
What... What was that?
おそらく　あの２人は　本当に
大門カイトを愛していたのかと…。
I am afraid they truly loved Daimon Kaito.
Lo...ve?
もう一つだけ　教えてくれ。
あの人は？　真方ジンは？
Tell me one more thing! What about Makata Jin?
ＰＯＧに捕まっています。
彼は…　私の親友でした。
He is being held captive by the POG.
He was a dear friend of mine.
はっ。
互いに　パズルの腕を競いあった…。
We always competed using puzzles.
君とルーク君のようにね。
Not unlike you and Rook.
カイト…　まさか…。
Kaito, don't tell me...
カイト！
（キュービック）カイト！
Kaito!
止めなくちゃ！
あれ　愚者のパズルなんでしょう？！
We must stop him! That's a Fools' Puzzle!
We can't stop him.
止められないよ。
ええっ？！
カイトは　お父さんと　お母さんに
お別れをしに行ったんだから。
He's going to say goodbye to his parents.
He must get in a basket and move along the ropes according to the rules of Ghost Leg.
カゴに乗って　アミダの要領で
進んでいく。
When the basket reaches the end, one flame goes out.
カゴが　石舞台にたどりつくたびに
炎が一つ消える。
すべての炎が消えると…→
When all the flames go out...
...the basket falls.
カゴは穴に落ちる。
すべての炎を消し　すべてのカゴを
落として　ゴールを目指す。
Reach the goal by putting out all flames and making every basket fall.
You're amazing, Kaito. But...
すごいよ　カイト君…　でも…。
行っちゃダメだよ…　カイト！
Don't go, Kaito!
違う…　俺とは…　パズルの重みが…。
He's totally different... He doesn't feel the weight of the puzzle.
I see, so this is his answer.
そっか。　それが　カイトの答え。
このパズルは　この俺の手で
心の声
絶対に解放してやる。
I'll solve this puzzle myself!
父さんと母さんを奪った
心の声
このパズルを！
This puzzle that took my parents away!
いや　どんなパズルもだ。
心の声
No, every puzzle!
悪いのは　パズルじゃない。
裏切るのは　いつも人間…。
It isn't the puzzle's fault.
It's always the person who made it who betrays us.
そう。
心の声
ジンの言うとおりだ。　聞こえる。
Jin was right.
I can hear it.
こいつも　ホントは
心の声
もう人殺しなんか　したくない。
It doesn't want to take any more lives!
心の声
早く解いてほしいって
俺に言ってるんだ！
It's telling me to solve it quick!
心の声
だから…　絶対に解いてやる！
So, I will solve it!
（ギャモン）マジで解きやがった。
I can't believe he solved it.
パズルが　ありがとうって言ってるよ。
The puzzle's thanking me.
父さん　母さん…。　くっ。
Dad! Mom!
ルーク！　俺は　パズルを解く！
Rook! I'll keep solving puzzles! And...
「そして…　ジンを…
ジンを助ける！」。
And I'll save Jin!
あとは　彼らを信じるほかないか。
I can only believe in them from now on.
それで　いいだろう…　ジン。
Fine by me. Right, Jin?
遠いよ…　カイト…。
You're so far away, Kaito...
tsukue no ue de umareta sekai
This world born on my table.
ichiban saki ni kimi ni misetakatta
I wanted you to see it first.
karappo no heya sotto nukedashite hashiri hajimeteta
I sneaked out of the empty room and started to run.
iki hazamasete oka wo noboru to
As I got to the top of the hill, out of breath,
kimi ga saki ni tsuite matteita ne
you were already there waiting for me.
takusan no hajimete kimi to mitsuketa takaramono datta
It was the first of many treasures we would find together.
kanashisa de afureta toki wa
When sorrow was overflowing in me,
nanimo iwazu ni tada soba ni ite kureta ne
you just silently stayed by my side.
ima de mo wasurenai yo
I still haven't forgotten that.
mata aou ne yakusoku wo shiyou
Let's promise we'll meet again.
kie wa shinai ano hi no sayonara
The goodbye of that day we'll never forget.
boku no subete kimi ga kureta michi
All I have I got from you,
zutto kokoro no naka hikaru yo
and it will all shine in my heart forever.